In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled by some transcendental entity or law?
Is it like the hand of God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no control, even over his own will.
Can't we go any faster?
No.
Any faster and it'll be too hard on Griffith.
They're catching up.
Feel no shame about shape
Weather changes their phrase
Even mother will show you another way
So put your glasses on
Nothing will be wrong
There's no blame. There's no fame
It's up to you
The first words should be found
Whatever holds you back
I...
...can...
I can get it off
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Don't know why you're afraid
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late
Eve of the Feast
First unit, continue pursuit!
Second unit, follow my lead!
To the valley!
At this rate, they'll catch up
with us any second!
We have no choice!
Should we attack?
No, we'll make it!
We thought we'd welcome
you with bows and arrows.
I'm counting on you to look after Griffith.
We'll take good care of him, big sister.
We're going to annihilate our
pursuers here, once and for all!
Bastards!
Charge!
What happened?
Stop right there!
Bastard!
Don't move.
Now slowly put your
weapons down and surrender!
I'm sure you thought you could revive
your group with this man's return, but...
Stop it!
Behold!
This man will never fight again!
He will never ride a horse,
nor hold a sword again...
He can't even stand on his own two feet!
You've made a grave mistake.
There is not a single shred
of hope left for any of you.
Hey, it's not true, is it?
What that bastard said
was a load of bullshit, right?
Screw you, guys! I'll ask him myself.
You can't do that.
What do you mean?
Griffith can't give you an answer.
You've got to be kidding.
So his throat got a little dry living in prison?
And that's why...
What the hell!
This is supposed to be our new beginning!
We were going to make a fresh start
after we rescued Griffith, right?
For a year we've lived like squirming
bugs, losing half our men...
But after believing for so long that all
we had to do was get Griffith back...
This is what we get?
You know, I had a feeling it would
turn out like this, seriously...
But...
But even so...
What are we going to do?
What on earth are we going to do now?
It's not like we've
been totally wiped out.
And we have you, Casca...
There's no Band of
the Hawk without Griffith.
You all should know that.
Yeah, but if that's the...
Casca's pushed herself
harder than anyone else.
So stop making unreasonable demands.
Yeah, but...
What about us...
Please give me...
...some time.
We still have time until the others join us.
Let me think this over until then.
Hey, wait up!
What is there to think over?
What are you planning?
You're not thinking of continuing...
What were you...
...about to say back there?
That if it's a battle of your own choosing...
...then you'd better settle it yourself.
That shows... how strong you are.
Because for us, even if we started
something, we can't always finish it.
Can you really look Griffith
in the eye now and say that?
We're all weak.
So we cling to others and to dreams...
We cling to kind words of comfort...
and even to harsh words of rebuke.
All I've wanted was someone
to cling to... To be by my side.
I'll go check on Griffith.
Griffith, let's change your bandages.
Whether it's a good dream or a bad dream...
No one feels good when
woken up in the middle of one...
So are you going back to traveling
and perfecting your combat skills?
I guess. And you?
Well...
Perhaps I'll bring along the guys that
are left and form a band of thieves.
That way, I'm sure we can
at least take care of Griffith...
I'll come too.
You already left us once, remember?
You have no obligation
to stick with us any longer.
But...
...you do?
Sure, I'm still one
of the Band of the Hawk.
But you're different.
You've already begun
fighting your own battles.
Leave behind those
who can no longer stand up.
That's the law
of the battlefield, isn't it?
But that aside...
You better be sure to take
Casca with you this time.
She's too much of a straight arrow
to be leading a pack of thieves.
A thief with a conscience? No thanks...
Not for me!
I mean it.
Take her with you,
even if you have to drag her.
Commander!
Commander Guts!
Hey, are you planning to leave
us again without saying a word?
If you go, please let us go with you!
We've all talked it over and agree...
Not one of us wishes otherwise.
You guys...
As long as you're there...
We'll make it through, somehow.
Commander!
Please take us with you...
Commander...
Please, Commander...
Perhaps...
...this has been my home all along.
I didn't realize it until this very moment...
Everything I wanted back then
is right here in front of me now.
Why?
Why do I never realize
what I have until it is lost?
Griffith's hands...
I never realized how small they were...
He tried to grasp everything
with these two hands...
Just by placing this hand on my shoulder...
...he always made my fears subside...
He saved me time after time...
Now I must do the same for him.
Oh...
Um...
Um, I...
Sorry...
I'll go get more bandages...
Griffith, st...
Hey...
How's Griffith?
He just fell asleep...
Something wrong?
No, nothing's wrong...
What the hell's going on?
No, really, it's nothing!
So you're crying over nothing?
Did something happen to Griffith?
No, stop!
It's not that!
Hey...
I'm sorry...
I can't go...
What?
I-I can't go with you...
Griffith...
...he's so small...
...and he's trembling so much...
When he used to be
so proud and dignified...
I can't leave him behind...
I can't leave him like that...
I'm sorry...
I'll stay...
...as well.
You're through clinging
to other people's dreams...
You have your own battles
to fight, remember?
You have to go...
If you're Griffith's true friend...
...you have to leave.
Even without me, you have to go.
Why are you trembling
with fear in a place like this?
Let's go...
I still want to play some more!
The sun hasn't set yet.
Griffith!
But how?
Did he hear us?
I'll go after him!
Go tell the others!
I've rested too long...
It's time to go...
It's not over yet...
As long as that cobblestone path
keeps leading me on...
Griffith...
Supper's ready.
Oh, were you asleep?
Sorry...
...but we need to get some air in here...
Where am I?
What?
Is there something on my face?
You were dreaming about
the old days again, weren't you?
A dream...
I see. That's all it was.
It's been a while since any
of the guys came by to see us.
I wonder what they're all up to?
I wonder if that guy's still waving
his big sword around somewhere?
The past feels like nothing
more than a dream now.
Hey! Guts!
Leave Pippin alone!
Go wash your hands!
Yes, Mother!
Many things happened...
But they're all just distant memories now.
I think I'm much more suited to this lifestyle...
My life with you and
our boy, just the three of us...
This kind of peaceful life is not so bad.
It's called a behelit, the Egg of the King.
The owner of
this necklace is destined to hold...
...the world in his hands,
in exchange for his flesh and blood.
In exchange for his flesh and blood?
Griffith...
...was it really me who drove you to this?
Am I responsible
for what has become of you?
What should I do?
What do you want me to do?
What can I do for you now?
What's that?
What the...
A solar eclipse...
Griffith!
Stay away!
Guts!
What the hell is that?
Soldiers?
Can it be the Midland army?
I don't know...
I don't know what it is...
But it's ominous...
Griffith!
Don't come near me!
If you touch me now...
If you grasp my shoulder now...
I'll never again...
I'll never again... you.
Griffith.
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight. You're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying your crown?
I'm spending my glass, walking back.
So wear my glass. You're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...